BIKASH GURUNG

COMPUTER SCIENCE MAJOR

+977-9817119087

⊠ bikash.grg2222@gmail.com

https://bikashgrg.github.io/

linkedin.com/in/bikash-g-830527112

PROFILE SUMMARY

A highly proficient, goal-oriented & adaptable Computer Science & Engineering graduate with strong problem-solving abilities marked by innovation & creativity. Acquired key technical skills & competencies projects multiple through technically challenging trainings, targeting core subjects of Computer Science. Focused on refining my technical knowledge & professional skills through specialized learning in Artificial Intelligence at graduate level.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Web Development: HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.is, MongoDB
- Programming: Java, Python, MySQL,
- Other: Git, GitHub, Android Studio, WordPress, Express.js, MS Office

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Leadership
- Teamwork
- Critical Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Attention to Detail
- Time Management
- Organization & Planning
- **Efficacious Communication**
- Analytical & Inductive Reasoning

CERTIFICATIONS

- JavaScript (2017) Issued by: Udemy Credential ID: UC-MOUHWZR5/
- Web Development (2017) Issued by: Internshala Credential ID: A158DfEf-656A-9FE5-1771-8A7D6F0EQFE

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.) Computer Science & Engineering

Lovely Professional University | Punjab, India 2015 - 2019 CGPA: 7.68/10.0 (69.12%) | EOF: Level 6 Credits: 189

Senior School Certificate Examination (SSCE)

Army Public School | CBSE | Dagshai, India 2014 - 2015Marks: 82.40% | Discipline: Science (Non-Medical)

Secondary School Examination (SSE)

Army Public School | CBSE | Dagshai, India 2012 - 2013

Marks: 87.40% | CGPA: 9.2/10.0

WORK EXPERIENCE

Management Trainee

SHL | Gurgaon, India

Sep 2019 - April 2021

- · Learn about the common roles and operations for all staff, as well as the procedure and strategies that affect the overall product team
- Work closely with engineering team to make time/feature trade-offs efficiently
- Mentor and train recruits to help improve their faith and abilities
- Conduct product technological research, test programs and review IT products to help and eradicate any defects
- Interprets and analyse IT products data to mine statistical insights and develop reports based on the acquired data
- · Won the best employee of the quarter within my team

Intern - Full Stack Development

Cognizant | Pune, India

Jan 2019 - Apr 2019

- · Worked in a diverse, experienced & agile team to define requirements, conduct research and develop end-to-end solutions in coordination with
- Led the effort to build a responsive website, developed user-interface architecture and designed navigation for improving usability
- Participated in forums, seminars and conferences for the purpose of career advancement, collaboration and collection of knowledge necessary for the execution of project projects and decision-making
- Gained valuable exposure in developing, coding, unit testing, and debugging new highly complex software solutions or enhancements to existing software

PROJECTS

Camping Website

https://salty-lowlands-73728.herokuapp.com

May 2019

- Made a website where users can find and add campground at different prices using Nodejs, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Expressjs and MongoDB
- Created UI authentication for login and sign up using different modules of
- Implementing RESTful API for defining the routes of the website

LANGUAGES

- English Professional Working Proficiency
- Native/Bilingual Proficiency
- Native/Bilingual Proficiency

Car Service Application

https://github.com/Bikashgrg/CarServiceApp

Nov 2018

- Made an app where users can find nearest service center or can call their home for the car services using android studio, java and firebase
- Implemented firebase in app for sign up and login process
 - Used animation, location, toast, google maps API for making app more functional



X EXTRACURRICULAR

Volunteer Member

National Service Scheme (LPU) | Punjab, India

Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

- Managed & organized Republic Day celebrations in a public school to make the day special for children via singing & recreational activities
- Participated in plantation drives, water conservation seminars, donation drives and health-related community events.

University Representative - SAU Festival

BBA University | Lucknow, India

Feb 2016

Participant - One World Mega Event

Lovely Professional University | Punjab, India

Nov 2015 and Nov 2016

YouthVibe Football Tournament

Lovely Professional University | Punjab, India

Oct 2016

Interschool Football Tournament

Pinegrove School | Kasauli, India

Sep 2012